Do I really have to work out on TRT? Uh,
isn't the testosterone enough?
>> So, you should be working out. They're
two It's a good question. They're
they're two independent things. You
should be working out anyway. So, should
you be working out on TRT? You should
be. Should you be working out if you're
not on TRT? You should be. Do it. You
need to do it. Extremely important for
your health. So, you should be doing it
regardless. Um, if the, you know, maybe
the bigger question is there, you know,
am I going to get results? Like, what
are we talking about here? like they
want to know if they're going to gain
muscle or lose fat or to get these kinds
of things. Um, you know, there's
actually uh a study that showed if you
ramp up the dose high enough, you will
get a, you know, you will get a response
from testosterone without any real
stimulus, you know, as far as weight
training or that kind of thing. I think
that was an injectable dose of somewhere
like 600 milligrams, which you're not
going to, no one's prescribing you that,
right? And I don't recommend doing that.
Please don't do that. Um, but uh, so
it's possible if the dose goes high
enough, but also that's silly. Why would
you do that and then not exercise too,
right? So, um, so it it's very important
that the people who do best with hormone
replacement therapy are the folks who
pair it with a good lifestyle.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. So, you're getting you're getting
your good exercise, you're getting a
good diet, you're getting your good
sleep, you're living, you know, you're
you're um, you know, dealing with your
stress in in positive ways. All those
things come together. It all works works
very good. So, I would say yes. Yes, you
do have to and and you should. And I
harass my patients if they don't. So do
it.